Let me introduce you two.
This is a top Whampoa Military Academy graduate,
Li Mingyuan.
Ever since he joined the department,
he's solved one major case after another,
making him our finest asset here.
Mingyuan,
Xu Jie has only been here for six months,
but...
he's the sharpest lad in our department.
Starting today,
you'll be taking him under your wing.
All right.
Mentor.
I'll take you to the hospital.
Mentor... Mentor...
It was him, wasn't it?
He forced you, right?
Mentor...
Mentor, I'm sorry.
I didn't want to do that.
I wanted to be a good cop.
You've always done well.
If only...
If only you'd been my mentor from the start.
A Browning 1900.
A very common pistol.
There's something off about this bullet.
This bullet...
seems to be for a Type 38 rifle.
6.5 mm caliber,
75.70 mm in length.
That's right. A Type 38 rifle.
The Japanese military's primary combat weapon.
Alright.
This is the police station's main office.
Upstairs are the archives, meeting rooms,
and the Chief's office.
Let me show you around.
This is the police department's top detective,
Captain Li Mingyuan.
Hello, Captain Li.
Let's go.
A few officers at Rongcheng Police Station got drunk today
and talked about the Lian family's case.
Two years ago, Uncle Lian was in a car accident.
The case was quickly closed as an accident,
but there's actually a confidential file at the station.
It contains information on the officers
and everyone involved.
With this file,
we might find the real killer
of Uncle and Aunt Lian.
I knew it was you.
What are you doing here?
Let go of me!
You first.
Why did you sneak into the police station?
Regarding my family's case,
there's a confidential file kept here.
I just want to see it.
Unauthorized personnel
aren't allowed into the archives to view files.
Just let me take a lo—
Listen to me.
Officers patrol the archives on a regular schedule.
If you don't want to get riddled with bullets,
get out of here right now.
Right.
You're right.
Then I'll leave.
Leave?
Hand it over.
Three.
Here, take it back.
Dr. Hao,
how long will it take for him to recover?
Acupuncture is only a supplementary treatment.
A sickness of the heart needs medicine for the mind.
Just take it slow.
Shuisheng.
Brother Lian has a few questions for you.
That night...
the group of people you saw...
No.
The ghosts you saw...
inside the coffin they were carrying,
what was inside?
Could it be...
Stop!
The killer wasn't smuggling cloth,
but weapons.
A mole in the police is in cahoots with the Japanese,
covering up the truth for them.
A partnership.
Deal.
That man is Sun Changgen.
Cousin of Sun Hanji from the Shipboard Guild.
That old bastard Sun Hanji really is dirty.
Shen Tieshan
died under suspicious circumstances.
Hurry, hurry!
No wonder in the Sea Goddess Temple murder,
they chose to hide the body here.
What do you mean?
Think about it.
A murder happened in Net Cave,
so fishermen won't dare come near.
Over time, this place
became completely abandoned.
Perfect for stashing dirty cargo.
Killing two birds with one stone.
The situation is complicated now.
If these weapons flow into Rongcheng,
once war breaks out,
the consequences will be catastrophic.
What are you doing?
Take them out!
They're heavily guarded.
Can't you see?
There are guards posted all around.
Even if you could take on a hundred men,
you couldn't survive being swarmed!
Then you tell me, what do we do now?
Surround the area!
Captain Li! Captain Li!
What's all this about?
Captain Li, Captain Li, please don't!
Someone reported contraband hidden here.
I must conduct a thorough search.
Captain Li...
Don't listen to their nonsense.
There's only some junk in here.
Whether it's junk or not,
we'll know once we take a look.
Wait, please don't!
Director Zhou.
What are you doing here?
Someone reported contraband here.
I've already searched this place with my men.
There's nothing illegal.
Take your men and head back.
Yes, Director Zhou.
Pull back!
Director Zhou...
Thank goodness you showed up.
Let me tell you this.
I can help you once,
but not a second time.
This place has been compromised.
Move your goods right now.
Yes, sir.
Quick, quick! Hurry up!
Move, move, move!
Quick! Over here!
Brother Lian, what are they doing?
Shut up.
Follow them.
Move it, move it! Hurry!
You two, take them and keep watch inside.
The rest of you, follow me!
Yes, sir! Right away!
Open the crates.
Brother Lian,
they're all Japanese Type 38 rifles!
We hit the jackpot!
Take them all back.
Yes, sir!
Brother Lian, everything is ready.
We can't carry off the rest of the gunpowder,
but are we really going to blow it up just like that?
Blow it up.
Leaving it behind will only cause trouble.
Where are the guns?
Where's the shipment?
Where the hell did you put the shipment?
It was all locked in the warehouse last night!
Mr. Matsui...
It was all here...
Sun Hanji!
At all costs,
track down every last bit of that shipment!
U-Understood!
Cheers!
What's got you so thrilled?
A windfall fell right into our laps!
We hit the jackpot this time.
Brother Mingyuan, it's rare to see you here.
What tea would you like?
Yongtai green tea.
Where did you stash the goods?
What goods?
You're going back on your word!
How about this?
Tomorrow, I'll take the Sanshan Gang boys
and seize that arms shipment in one sweep.
No way.
They're heavily guarded.
If you try to take it by force,
it'll be a pyrrhic victory.
Besides, let me remind you,
this case is police business.
Xu Jie was a cautionary tale.
Can your police department even be trusted?
Chief Song
is about to retire,
so he won't get involved.
Even if you manage
to move the weapons to the station today,
the mole will find a way
to swap them back
untouched tomorrow.
It'll all be for nothing.
Here's the plan.
Tomorrow, I'll stage a raid
to flush them out
and make them move the weapons.
You make your move then.
Brilliant.
Right.
Now, I agreed to work with you,
but I never promised
I'd hand the weapons over to you.
Right, they belong to us!
We won't hand them over.
Snap out of it!
The mastermind will soon realize
that you have them.
These weapons—
everyone has their eye on them.
You won't survive attacks from all sides.
These arms aren't a prize to you,
they're a hot potato!
It's not too late to turn them over to me.
I promise they'll be kept in a safe place.
You've been nagging forever.
I know all that.
You did this on purpose.
You used me to seize the guns on purpose,
drawing dangerous heat right onto yourself!
What the hell are you after?
Painting a giant target on your back...
You won't even see your death coming!
Don't trouble yourself over me.
Brother Mingyuan.
Where are the goods?
You can have them,
on one condition.
Name it.
Trade them for my parents' case files.
Impossible.
Then see yourself out.
Brother Mingyuan, why leave so soon?
You haven't even touched your tea.
You...
The armory exploded,
and over a thousand rifles vanished.
Find a way to get those guns back for me.
Yes, Mr. Matsui.
Regarding my family's case,
there's a confidential file kept here.
I want to see it.
Where are the goods?
Trade them for my parents' case files.